‘The blanket never did anything.’ That’s what I overheard some of the people who work here say as I was being escorted down into the Archives to give this statement. They were standing together over the kettle on a coffee break, saying this over and over like it was some sort of absolute truth. Or maybe they were just kidding around. I was ushered on too quickly to be able to tell. 

I am here because, well, the blanket did something. *My* blanket did something, anyway. Or, maybe it wasn’t actually the blanket, but something else. It helps me feel better if I ascribe blame to the blanket, though, because if it wasn’t the blanket, I think I’m in big trouble.

I get insomnia on occasion. Sometimes, it manifests in nights where I’m exhausted and silent in mind, yet I still find myself spending hours staring blankly at the ceiling, willing to be overtaken by a sleep that will never come. Other nights, as the moon rises high, I am overcome with a paralysing fear that falling asleep means I will never wake up, and so I spend such nights in the company of the warm glow of my television. The latter is what occurred a week ago, so as it came time for me to climb into bed, I queued up a couple of movies and prepared for a long night.

Things started going weird at about 2AM. That was when I first noticed the fog. It must have been slowly filling into the room for a while, because if it had come on so suddenly I think it would have startled me more. As it was, I realised that I was having to squint to see my screen more than I reasonably should have. I turned up my brightness only to see condensation in the air, thick and oppressive. And all at once, the fear that had kept me awake intensified to a fever pitch, and despite my many blankets, a chill settled into my bones.

I raced to grab and turn on the torch I always keep on my nightstand, looking for where the fog might be coming from. Had I left a window open? Was there a flood in my kitchen causing all this? But the light couldn’t cut through the fog, droplets in the air scattering the beam within a metre so that all I could see was a distorted mass of fog, bending the shadows into slowly pulsating figures. I let out a gasp and burrowed under my covers with my light source, hoping it would protect me from whatever was happening.

I curled in around myself, torch pointed out from my abdomen, and I tried to breathe through the heavy, wet air that infiltrated my hastily-assembled blanket fort. Hours passed, and then, at around 4AM, I felt something grab at my leg through the blanket.

I screamed. Loudly as I could, for a long time, and pulled the blankets even tighter around myself. I think I must have passed out at some point, because the next thing I was aware of was the sun peeking through under the cracks of the blanket. I called in sick to work, and spent the day sleeping on a friend’s couch.

The fog didn’t come back the next night, or the night after, or any night since. But I asked my neighbours if they saw the fog. None of them had. It seems like none of them heard me screaming, either. Maybe being under the blanket cut off the sound. Or maybe it was the fog. I hope it was the blanket.

One of my neighbours recommended that I come here and tell you my story when they coaxed the whole story out of me. So here I am. I’m hoping you all have some better idea of what’s going on than I do, because I'm afraid if it returns, the fog and its shadows won't leave me behind again.